Next subject: Kowalski, Leon.
Engineer, waste disposal.
File section: New employee, six days.
Calling Mr. Webber...
- Come in.
- ...please report to Zone A Sector 9.
Replication Center Level 9,
we have a B1 security alert.
Stand by for ID check, please.
Sit down.
Replication Center Level 9,
we have a B1 security alert.
Stand by for...
Care if I talk?
I'm kind of nervous when I take tests.
Just please don't move.
Oh, sorry.
I already had an IQ test.
I don't think I've had one of these.
Reaction time is a factor,
so pay attention.
Now, answer as quickly as you can.
Sure.
1187 at Hunterwasser.
That's the hotel.
- What?
- Where I live.
- Nice place?
- Yeah, sure, I guess.
Is that part of the test?
No. Just warming you up. That's all.
It's not fancy or anything.
You're in a desert,
walking along in the sand, when--
Is this the test now?
Yes. You're in a desert,
walking along in the sand...
- ...when you look down--
- What one?
- What?
- What desert?
Doesn't make any difference.
It's completely hypothetical.
- But how come I'd be there?
- Maybe you're fed up.
Maybe you wanna be by yourself.
Who knows?
You look down and see a tortoise.
- It's crawling towards you--
- Tortoise? What's that?
- You know what a turtle is?
- Of course.
Same thing.
I've never seen a turtle.
But I understand what you mean.
You reach down,
you flip the tortoise over on its back.
Do you make up these questions,
Mr. Holden?
Or do they write them down for you?
The tortoise lays on its back,
its belly baking in the sun...
...beating its legs,
trying to turn itself over, but it can't...
...not without your help.
- You're not helping.
- What do you mean I'm not?
I mean, you're not helping.
Why is that, Leon?
They're just questions, Leon.
In answer to your query,
they're written down for me.
It's a test designed to provoke
an emotional response.
Shall we continue?
Describe in single words only the
good things that come into your mind...
...about your mother.
- My mother?
- Yeah.
Let me tell you about my mother.
A new life awaits you
in the Off-world colonies.
The chance to begin again...
...in a golden land of opportunity
and adventure.
A new life awaits you
in the Off-world colonies.
The chance to begin again...
...in a golden land of opportunity
and adventure.
The custom-tailored...
...genetically engineered
humanoid Replicant...
...designed especially for your needs.
So come on, America.
Let's put out...
Give me four.
No, four. Two, two. Four.
And noodles.
Hey.
He say you under arrest, Mr. Deckard.
Got the wrong guy, pal.
He say you Blade Runner.
Tell him I'm eating.
Captain Bryant...
Bryant, huh?
Yellow 3.
Climb and maintain 4000.
Final descent.
Now on glide path. Mark course.
Over the landing threshold.
Hi, Deck.
Bryant.
You wouldn't have come
if I just asked you to. Sit down, pal.
Come on, don't be an asshole, Deckard.
I've got four skin-jobs walking the streets.
They jumped a shuttle Off-world,
killed the crew and passengers.
They found the shuttle drifting
off the coast two weeks ago...
...so we know they're around.
Embarrassing.
No, not embarrassing. No one's ever
gonna find out they're down here.
Because you're gonna spot them
and air them out.
I don't work here anymore.
Give it to Holden.
- He's good.
- I did.
He can breathe okay
as long as nobody unplugs him.
He's not good enough.
Not good as you.
I need you, Deck.
Now, this is a bad one, the worst yet.
I need the old Blade Runner.
I need your magic.
I was quit
when I come in here, Bryant.
I'm twice as quit now.
Stop right where you are.
You know the score, pal?
If you're not cop, you're little people.
No choice, huh?
No choice, pal.
I already had an IQ test this year.
I don't think I've ever
had one of these.
Reaction time is a factor,
so please pay attention.
- Answer as quickly as you can.
- Yeah, sure.
1187 at Hunterwasser.
Yeah. That's the hotel.
- What?
- Where I live.
- Nice place?
- Yeah, sure, I guess.
There was an escape from
the Off-world colonies two weeks ago.
Six Replicants:
three male, three female.
They slaughtered 23 people
and jumped a shuttle.
An aerial patrol spotted
the ship off the coast.
No crew, no sight of them.
Three nights ago they tried to break
into Tyrell Corporation.
Two of them got fried running
through an electrical field.
We lost the others.
On the possibility they might try
to infiltrate as employees...
...I had Holden go over and run
Voight-Kampff tests on the new workers.
Looks like he got himself one.
So you look down and you see
a tortoise. It's crawling towards you.
- Tortoise? What's that?
- That's Leon.
Ammunition loader
on intergalactic runs.
He can lift 400-pound atomic loads
all day and night.
The only way you can hurt him
is to kill him.
I don't get it. What do they risk coming
back to Earth for? That's unusual. Why...?
What do they want
out of the Tyrell Corporation?
Well, you tell me, pal.
That's what you're here for.
- What's this?
- Nexus 6. Roy Batty.
Incept date: 2016.
Combat model.
Optimum self-sufficiency.
Probably the leader.
This is Zhora.
She's trained for
an Off-world kick murder squad.
Talk about Beauty and the Beast.
She's both.
The fourth skin-job is Pris,
a basic pleasure model.
The standard item for military clubs
in the outer colonies.
They were designed to copy human beings
in every way except their emotions.
The designers reckoned
after a few years...
...they might develop
their own emotional responses.
Oh, hate, love, fear, anger, envy.
So they built in a fail-safe device.
- Which is what?
- Four-year lifespan.
Now, there's a Nexus 6
over at the Tyrell Corporation.
- I want you to go put the machine on it.
- And if the machine doesn't work?
Do you like our owl?
It's artificial?
Of course it is.
Must be expensive.
Very. I'm Rachael.
Deckard.
It seems you feel our work
is not a benefit to the public.
Replicants are like any other machine:
They're either a benefit or a hazard.
If they're a benefit,
it's not my problem.
May I ask you a personal question?
Sure.
Have you ever retired a human
by mistake?
No.
- But in your position, that is a risk.
- Is this to be an empathy test?
Capillary dilation
of the so-called blush response?
Fluctuation of the pupil.
Involuntary dilation of the iris.
We call it Voight-Kampff for short.
Mr. Deckard, Dr. Eldon Tyrell.
Demonstrate it.
I wanna see it work.
- Where's the subject?
- I wanna see it work on a person.
I wanna see a negative
before I provide you with a positive.
What's that gonna prove?
Indulge me.
On you?
Try her.
It's too bright in here.
Do you mind if I smoke?
It won't affect the test.
All right, I'm gonna ask you
a series of questions.
Just relax and answer them
as simply as you can.
It's your birthday.
Someone gives you a calfskin wallet.
I wouldn't accept it.
Also, I'd report the person
who gave it to me to the police.
You've got a little boy.
He shows you his butterfly collection...
...plus the killing jar.
I'd take him to the doctor.
You're watching television.
Suddenly you realize
there's a wasp crawling on your arm.
I'd kill it.
You're reading a magazine. You come
across a full-page nude photo of a girl.
Is this testing whether I'm a Replicant
or a lesbian, Mr. Deckard?
Just answer the questions, please.
You show it to your husband.
He likes it so much
he hangs it on your bedroom wall.
--Bush outside your window?
I wouldn't let him.
orange body, green legs?
Why not?
I should be enough for him.
One more question.
You're watching a stage play,
a banquet is in progress.
The guests are enjoying
an appetizer of raw oysters.
The entrée consists of boiled dog.
Would you step out
for a few moments, Rachael?
Thank you.
She's a Replicant, isn't she?
I'm impressed.
How many questions
does it usually take to spot one?
- I don't get it, Tyrell.
- How many questions?
Twenty, thirty, cross-referenced.
It took more than a hundred for Rachael,
didn't it?
She doesn't know.
She's beginning to suspect, I think.
Suspect?
How can it not know what it is?
Commerce is our goal here at Tyrell.
"More human than human"
is our motto.
Rachael is an experiment,
nothing more.
We began to recognize in them
a strange obsession.
After all, they are emotionally
inexperienced, with only a few years...
...in which to store up the experiences
which you and I take for granted.
If we gift them with a past, we create
a cushion or a pillow for their emotions...
...then consequently
we can control them better.
Memories.
You're talking about memories.
HOLDEN Reaction
time is a factor, so please pay attention.
- Now, answer as quickly as you can.
- Sure.
- 1187 at Hunterwasser.
- Yeah. That's the hotel.
- What?
- Where I live.
- Nice place?
- Yeah, sure, I guess.
- Is that part of the test?
- No.
Kowalski.
Time...
...enough.
Did you get your precious photos?
Someone was there.
Men?
Policemen?
Aha.
Fiery the angels fell
Deep thunder rolled around their shores
Burning with the fires of Orc
You not come here! Illegal!
Hey! Hey!
Cold! Those are my eyes! Freezing!
Yes.
Questions.
Hey! Hey!
Morphology. Longevity. Incept dates.
Don't know.
I don't know such stuff.
I just do eyes.
Just eyes, just genetic design.
Just eyes.
You Nexus, huh?
I design your eyes.
Chew...
...if only you could see
what I've seen with your eyes.
Now...
...questions.
I don't know answers.
Who does?
Tyrell.
He knows everything.
Tyrell Corporation?
He big boss. Big genius.
He design your mind.
Your brain, huh?
Smart.
Very cold.
Not an easy man to see...
Give me coat.
...I guess?
Sebastian.
He take you there.
Sebastian who?
J.F...
...Sebast...
Now...
...where...
...would we find this...
...J.F. Sebastian?
HOLDEN Let's continue, shall we?
Describe in single words...
...only the good things that come
into your mind about your mother.
- My mother?
- Yeah.
I'll tell you about my mother.
Voice-print identification.
Your floor number, please.
- Deckard, 97.
- Ninety-seven. Thank you. Danke.
I wanted to see you.
So I waited.
Let me help you.
What do I need help for?
I don't know why
he told you what he did.
Talk to him.
He wouldn't see me.
You want a drink?
No?
You think I'm a Replicant, don't you?
Look.
It's me with my mother.
Yeah?
Remember when you were six?
You and your brother snuck into an empty
building through a basement window.
You were gonna play doctor?
He showed you his, and when it got
to be your turn, you chickened and ran.
Remember that?
Did you ever tell anybody that?
Your mother, Tyrell, anybody, huh?
You remember the spider that lived
in the bush outside your window?
Orange body, green legs?
Watched her build a web all summer?
Then one day, there's a big egg in it.
The egg hatched...
- The egg hatched...
- And?
...and a hundred baby spiders
came out.
And they ate her.
Implants.
Those aren't your memories,
they're somebody else's.
They're Tyrell's niece's.
Okay.
Bad joke.
I made a bad joke.
You're not a Replicant.
Go home.
Okay?
No, really. I'm sorry.
Go home.
Want a drink?
I'll get you a drink.
I'll get a glass.
Hey!
You forgot your bag.
I'm lost.
Don't worry, I won't hurt you.
What's your name?
- Pris.
- Mine's J.F. Sebastian.
- Hi.
Oh, where were you going?
Home?
I don't have one.
We scared each other pretty good,
didn't we?
We sure did.
I'm hungry, J.F.
I got stuff inside.
You wanna come in?
I was hoping you'd say that.
Do you live in this building
all by yourself?
Yeah, I live here
pretty much alone right now.
No housing shortage around here.
Plenty of room for everybody.
Watch out for the water.
Must get lonely here, J.F.
Not really. I make friends.
They're toys. My friends are toys.
I make them.
It's a hobby. I'm a genetic designer.
Do you know what that is?
No.
Now.
Oh.
Yoo-hoo, home again.
Home again, home again, jiggidy-jig.
- Good evening, J.F.
- Evening, fellas.
They're my friends. I made them.
Where are your folks?
I'm sort of an orphan.
Oh. What about your friends?
I have some, but I have to find them.
I'll let them know
where I am tomorrow.
Oh?
Can I take those things for you?
They're soaked, aren't they?
Enhance 224 to 176.
Enhance.
Stop.
Move in.
Pull out, track right.
Stop.
Center and pull back.
Track 45 right.
Stop.
Center and stop.
Enhance 34 to 36.
Pan right and pull back.
Stop.
Enhance 34 to 46.
Pull back.
Wait a minute. Go right.
Stop.
Enhance 57-19.
Track 45 left.
Stop.
Enhance 15 to 23.
Give me a hard copy right there.
Fish?
I think it was manufactured locally.
Finest quality. Superior workmanship.
There is the maker's serial number.
9906947-XB71.
Interesting.
Not fish. Snake scale.
Snake.
Try Abdul Ben Hassan.
He make this snake!
Abdul Hassan?
I'm a police officer.
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
Artificial-snake license XB71,
that's you?
This is your work, huh?
Who did you sell it to?
My work? Not too many
could afford such quality.
How many?
- Very few.
- How few?
- Look, my friend--
- Taffey Lewis'.
Down in Fourth Sector, Chinatown.
Cross now. Cross now. Cross now.
Cross now. Cross now.
Bartender.
Taffey Lewis?
- Taffey.
- Yeah?
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
Blow.
You ever buy snakes
from the Egyptian, Taffey?
All the time, pal.
You ever see this girl, huh?
Never seen her. Buzz off.
Your licenses in order, pal?
Hey, Louie.
The man is dry. Give him one
on the house, okay? See?
Hello?
I've had people walk out on me before,
but not when...
...I was being so charming.
I'm in a bar, here now,
down in the Fourth Sector.
Taffey Lewis is on the line.
Why don't you come on down here
and have a drink?
I don't think so, Mr. Deckard.
That's not my kind of place.
Go someplace else?
MAN Ladies and gentlemen...
...Taffey Lewis presents
Miss Salome and the snake.
Watch her take the pleasure
from the serpent...
...that once corrupted man.
Excuse me, Miss Salome,
can I talk to you for a minute?
I'm from the American Federation
of Variety Artists.
Oh, yeah?
I'm not here to make you join.
No, ma'am. That's not my department.
Actually...
...I'm from the Confidential Committee
on Moral Abuses.
Committee of Moral Abuses?
There's been reports
that the management...
...has been taking liberties
with the artists.
I don't know nothing about it.
Have you felt yourself to be
exploited in any way?
How do you mean "exploited"?
Well, like to get this job.
I mean, did you do, or were you
asked to do, anything that's...
...lewd or unsavory or...
...otherwise repulsive
to your person, huh?
- Are you for real?
- Oh, yeah.
I'd like to check
your dressing room, if I may.
- For what?
- For holes.
Holes?
Well, you'd be surprised
what a guy would go through...
...to get a glimpse of a beautiful body.
No, I wouldn't.
Little...
...dirty holes they drill in the wall
so they can watch a lady undress.
- Is this a real snake?
- Of course it's not real.
Think I'd be working in a place like this
if I could afford a real snake?
So if somebody does try to exploit me,
who do I go to about it?
- Me.
- You're a dedicated man. Dry me.
The only thing they care about--
Hey!
Cross now. Cross now.
Don't walk. Don't walk.
Don't walk. Don't walk. Don't walk.
Cross now. Cross now.
Move! Get out of the way!
Deckard.
B26354.
Move on. Move on.
A minute.
Yeah, what do you want?
Tsingtao.
This enough?
Yeah.
Bryant.
Christ, Deckard, you look almost as bad
as that skin-job you left on the sidewalk.
I'm going home.
Could learn from this guy, Gaff.
He's a goddamn one-man
slaughterhouse, that's what he is.
Four more to go.
- Come on, Gaff, let's go.
- Three.
There's three to go.
There's four.
That skin-job you VK'd
at the Tyrell Corporation...
...Rachael, disappeared, vanished.
Didn't even know she was a Replicant.
Something to do with a brain implant,
says Tyrell.
Come on, Gaff.
Drink some for me, huh, pal?
Leon.
How old am I?
I don't know.
My birthday's April 10, 2017.
How long do I live?
Four years.
More than you.
Painful to live in fear, isn't it?
Nothing is worse than having
an itch you can never scratch.
I agree.
Wake up. Time to die.
Shakes?
Me too.
I get them bad.
It's part of the business.
I'm not in the business.
I am the business.
What if I go north?
Disappear.
Would you come after me?
Hunt me?
No.
No, I wouldn't.
I owe you one.
But somebody would.
Deckard...
...you know those files on me?
The incept date. The longevity.
Those things.
You saw them?
They're...
...classified.
But you're a policeman.
I...
...didn't look at them.
You know,
that Voight-Kampff test of yours...
...did you ever take that test yourself?
Deckard.
I dreamt music.
I didn't know if I could play.
I remember lessons.
I don't know if it's me
or Tyrell's niece.
You play beautifully.
Now you kiss me.
I can't rely on my--
Say, "Kiss me."
Kiss me.
I want you.
Again.
Put your hands on me.
- What you doing?
- I'm sorry. Just peeking.
Oh.
- How do I look?
- You look better.
- Just better?
- Well...
...you look beautiful.
Thanks.
How old are you?
Twenty-five.
- What's your problem?
- Methuselah syndrome.
What's that?
My glands, they grow old too fast.
- Is that why you're still on Earth?
- Yeah. I couldn't pass the medical.
Anyway...
...I kind of like it here.
I like you...
...just the way you are.
Hi, Roy.
Hi.
Gosh, you...
...really got some nice toys here.
This is the friend I was telling you about.
This is my savior, J.F. Sebastian.
Sebastian.
I like a man that stays put.
You live here all by yourself, do you?
Yes.
How about some breakfast?
I was just gonna make some.
Excuse me.
Well?
Leon...
What's going on?
There's only two of us now.
Then we're stupid and we'll die.
No, we won't.
No.
Knight takes queen, see?
Won't do.
Why are you staring at us, Sebastian?
Because...
...you're so different.
You're so perfect.
Yes.
What generation are you?
Nexus 6.
Ah. I knew it.
Because I do genetic design work
for the Tyrell Corporation.
There's some of me in you.
Show me something.
Like what?
Like anything.
We're no computers, Sebastian.
We're physical.
I think, Sebastian...
...therefore, I am.
Very good, Pris. Now show him why.
We've got a lot in common.
- What do you mean?
- Similar problems.
Accelerated decrepitude.
I don't know much
about biomechanics, Roy. I wish I did.
If we don't find help soon...
...Pris hasn't got long to live.
We can't allow that.
- Is he good?
- Who?
- Your opponent.
- Oh, Dr. Tyrell?
I've only beaten him once in chess.
He's a genius.
He designed you.
Maybe he could help.
I'd be happy to mention it to him.
Better if I talk to him in person.
But I understand
he's a sort of hard man to get to.
Yes.
Very.
Will you help us?
I can't.
We need you, Sebastian.
You're our best and only friend.
We're so happy you found us.
I don't think
there's another human being...
...in the whole world
who would've helped us.
66,000 Prosser & Ankovich. Hm.
Trade.
- Trade at two--
- Blue entry.
A Mr. J.F. Sebastian.
16417.
TYRELL At this hour?
What can I do for you, Sebastian?
Queen to bishop six. Check.
Nonsense.
Just a moment.
Queen to bishop six, ridiculous.
Queen...
...bishop six.
Hm.
Knight...
...takes queen.
What's on your mind, Sebastian?
What are you thinking about?
Bishop to king seven.
Checkmate.
Checkmate, I think.
Got a brainstorm, huh, Sebastian?
Milk and cookies
kept you awake, huh?
Let's discuss this.
You better come up, Sebastian.
Mr. Tyrell?
I...
I brought a friend.
I'm surprised
you didn't come here sooner.
It's not an easy thing
to meet your maker.
And what can he do for you?
Can the maker repair what he makes?
Would you like to be modified?
Stay here.
Had in mind something
a little more radical.
What...?
What seems to be the problem?
- Death.
Well, I'm afraid that's
a little out of my jurisdiction. You--
I want more life...
...father.
The facts of life.
To make an alteration in the...
...evolvement of
an organic life system is fatal.
A coding sequence cannot be revised
once it's been established.
Why not?
Because by the second day
of incubation...
...any cells that have undergone
reversion mutations...
...give rise to revertant colonies
like rats leaving a sinking ship.
Then the ship sinks.
What about EMS recombination?
We've already tried it.
Ethyl methane sulfonate is an
alkylating agent and a potent mutagen.
It created a virus so lethal...
...the subject was dead
before he left the table.
Then a repressor protein
that blocks the operating cells.
Wouldn't obstruct replication, but it
does give rise to an error in replication.
So that the newly formed DNA strand
carries a mutation...
...and you've got a virus again.
But this, all of this, is...
...academic.
You were made
as well as we could make you.
But not to last.
The light that burns twice as bright
burns half as long.
And you have burned
so very, very brightly, Roy.
Look at you.
You're the prodigal son.
You're quite a prize.
I've done...
...questionable things.
Also extraordinary things.
Revel in your time.
Nothing the god of biomechanics
wouldn't let you in heaven for.
Sorry, Sebastian.
Come. Come.
Body identified with Tyrell...
...is a 25-year-old male Caucasian.
Name: Sebastian, J.F. Sebastian.
Address: Bradbury Apartments,
Ninth Sector, NF46751.
I want you to go down there and--
This sector's closed to
ground traffic. What are you doing here?
- I'm working. What are you doing?
- Arresting you, that's what I'm doing.
I'm Deckard, Blade Runner.
26354. I'm filed and monitored.
Hold on. Checking.
Okay. Checked and cleared.
Have a better one.
- Hello.
- Hi. Is J.F. there?
- Who is it?
- This is Eddie, old friend of J.F.'s.
That's no way to treat a friend.
Home again, home again, jiggidy-jig.
Good evening, J.F.
Tea?
More tea?
Not very sporting to fire
on an unarmed opponent.
I thought you were
supposed to be good.
Aren't you the good man?
Come on, Deckard.
Show me...
...what you're made of.
Proud of yourself, little man?
- This is for Zhora.
- Ah!
- This is for Pris.
Come on, Deckard.
I'm right here,
but you've gotta shoot straight.
Straight doesn't seem
to be good enough!
Now it's my turn.
I'm gonna give you a few seconds
before I come.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Pris.
Ah!
I'm coming.
Deckard!
Four, five
How to stay alive?
I can see you!
Not yet!
Not...
Ah!
Five.
Yes.
You better get it up.
Or I'm gonna have to kill you.
Unless you're alive, you can't play.
And if you don't play...
Six, seven
Go to hell or go to heaven
Good, that's the spirit!
That hurt.
That was irrational of you.
Not to mention...
...unsportsmanlike.
Where are you going?
Quite an experience to live in fear,
isn't it?
That's what it is to be a slave.
I've...
...seen things
you people wouldn't believe.
Attack ships on fire
off the shoulder of Orion.
I watched C-beams...
...glitter in the dark
near the Tannhäuser Gate.
All those...
...moments will be lost...
...in time...
...like...
...tears...
...in rain.
Time to die.
You've done a man's job, sir.
I guess you're through, huh?
Finished.
It's too bad she won't live.
But then again, who does?
Rachael?
Do you love me?
I love you.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
Rachael?
It's too bad she won't live.
But then again, who does?